# **Devin Lehmacher**

308 108th Ave NE, Apt. C213, Bellevue, WA 98004 djl329@cornell.edu • +1 (864) 722–3014 • github.com/lehmacdj

**SUMMARY** 

Self motivated software engineer with proven commitment to programming in Haskell. 2+ years of industry experience developing concurrent cloud services that comprise Microsoft's Azure AD identity platform. Strong theoretical background in functional programming and programming language theory from university courses.

**EDUCATION** 

#### **Cornell University**

Aug 2015 — May 2019

■ Bachelors of Arts in Computer Science

Ithaca, NY

■ Cumulative GPA: 3.611

**EXPERIENCE** 

## Microsoft, Azure AD, Software Engineer II

Aug 2019 — Present

- Design, prototype, develop, instrument, and test new features for backend service
- Redmond, WA
- $\ \ \blacksquare$  Monitor and analyze metrics and logs for service to ensure quality of service
- Debug and fix bugs impacting customers' authentication
- Participate in regular security and privacy reviews to ensure compliance
- Coordinated sub-team of 4 through transition to service's general availability
- Prototyped and completed Cosmos DB migration to handle over 5x of the original load
- Integrated Polly, a C# fault handling library, with an existing cloud service

## Cornell University, Teaching Assistant

Feb 2016 — May 2019

Taught weekly sections with 25 students

Ithaca, NY

- Held weekly office hours to help students understand the course material
- Answered students' questions on Piazza course platform, during office hours, and after class
- Helped test, create, and plan future assignments
- Graded assignments and exams, giving students helpful feedback

## **Microsoft**, Software Engineering Intern

May 2018 — Aug 2018

Designed a microservice architecture for a new cloud service

- Redmond, WA
- Worked with team to determine what the service's critical features are
- Implemented a prototype of those features using Microsoft Service Fabric and Azure

#### Itron Inc., Intern

Jun 2017 — Aug 2017

- Created a dashboard to visualize available space for testing electrical meters
- Oconee, SC

- Utilized Transact-SQL to collect data for the dashboard
- Built and deployed reports to Sharepoint using Microsoft Reporting Services

#### **PROJECTS**

# Xi Compiler, compiler for a simple C-like programming language

- Collaborated with a group of 3 other students over the course of a semester
- Implemented parser, type checker, optimizer, and x86 assembly code generation
- Added object oriented features while maintaining backwards compatibility

# **Graph System**, Haskell knowlege graph console application

- Extensively uses algebraic effects via polysemy library to make code more testable
- Use GitHub Actions to ensure that test suite is run for all code changes
- Made several JSON schema migrations, requiring careful planning for backwards compatibility

### **Open Source**

- Submit pull requests and bug reports, contribute to feature discussions
- Made git credential daemon conform to the XDG directory specification
- Added missing library functions to Haskell libraries

# PortOS, minimal operating system running on a MIPS virtual machine

- Implemented multithreading with preemption, and TCP and UDP analogs
- Learned how to navigate and write a moderately sized (10,000 lines) C code base

# Interpreters, interpreters and type checkers for variety of languages

- a subset Scheme, System F, OCalf (a subset of OCaml), and several others
- Learned how to write REPLs using Haskeline and implement parsers using megaparsec

**SKILLS** 

Fluent: Haskell, C#, shell scripting, Azure, Git, Vim, Linux Familiar: REST, C, Java, OCaml, Rust, SQL, Python, Nix